Guide to the Maria Mitchell Papers, 1843-2016 (bulk 1853-1889)
Vassar College Libraries Archives and Special Collections
- SERIES X. GLASS PLATE NEGATIVES, 1871-1890
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1875 Nov 22 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "Duplicate"
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1875 Nov 24 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "The motion of the spots appears regular."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1875 Nov 25 (Neg. Box 10)
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1875 Nov 27 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "But one large spot on the western limb. The two small spots near the center are not visible."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1875 Nov 29 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Spot going off surrounded by faculae. From Nov. 29 to Dec. 12 no spots were visible. Observations were interrupted by clouds, to a very great degree, but when an opening in the clouds allowed observations, the sun's disk appeared free from spots. On Dec. 12 a very small spot surrounded by faculae was observed coming on but, after that date, could not be found. Dec. 14. A large spot was observed, with the telescope, on the very edge coming on."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Wylie, 1875 Dec 17 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: ""The spot first observed on the edge Dec. 14 seems to have divided into two. The penumbra and faculae are very marked. A group of spots near the center which has not appeared before is observed.” “Dec. 21 1875. A small group has appeared on the eastern limb. The two groups seen on Dec. 17 appear to be moving regularly across the disk.""
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Wylie, 1875 Dec 22 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "One large group near the center. The two small groups, one on the eastern limb one the western, could not be found."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Wylie, 1875 Dec 23 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "The large group moving regularly"
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Wylie, 1875 Dec 27 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "A small pair of spots on the western limb. From Dec 23 to Dec 27 Cloudy weather prevented photographing. From Dec. 27 to Jan. photographing was interrupted by Cloudy weather and high winds. Whenever an observation was made the sun's disk was free from spots except on Jan 10 when a very small group was seen on the western limb but after that date it could not be found"
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Banfield, 1876 Jan 20 (Neg. Box 16)
    Notes: "In this photograph a large spot is seen coming on. With the telescope a small spot was seen following the large one. A small group near the center and a small group on the western limb was seen with the telescope. The photograph is very poor."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1876 Jan 21 (Neg. Box 16)
    Notes: ""The motion of the large spot appears regular. The two groups observed with the telescope on Jan 20 appear to move regularly. The large spot is followed by two small ones. Jan 24. The motion appeared regular, but no other change was noticed since Jan. 21.""
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1876 Jan 26 (Neg. Box 16)
    Notes: "Two groups on the western limb, one of them near the edge, surrounded by faculae. The group which was seen near the edge on Jan 21 has disappeared. The group observed near the center on that date was now near the edge and the large spot had separated into group of one large one and several small ones. - Jan 30 No spots - Feb. 2 No spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Banfield, 1876 Feb 12 (Neg. Box 16)
    Notes: "A large spot with penumbra and followed by faculae is visible coming on. - Feb. 13 The motion of the spot appears regular - Feb. 16 The spot has divided into a chain of spots and is now near the center."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1876 Feb 19 (Neg. Box 16)
    Notes: "Feb. 18 1876, A chain of spots on the western limb. A chain of spots on the western limb. A very poor photograph."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1876 Feb 22 (Neg. Box 16)
    Notes: "The last spot of the chain on the very edge."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1876 Feb 26 (Neg. Box 16)
    Notes: "Feb. 28. Two small spots coming on. Two small spots on Eastern limb. One very faint and small."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1876 Mar 9 (Neg. Box 16)
    Notes: "A small spot coming on."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1876 May 10 (Neg. Box 16)
    Notes: "May 6, A spot appeared coming on. Two spots very near followed by two very small ones, too small to be seen on the photograph."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1876 May 11 (Neg. Box 16)
    Notes: "The very small spots have disappeared and but one spot is seen instead of the two very near as seen on May 10."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Banfield, 1876 May 13 12:20 PM (Neg. Box 16)
    Notes: "A spot on the western limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1876 May 18 (Neg. Box 16)
    Notes: "A group coming on. Two small groups on the eastern limb and a small group on the western limb above the center."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1876 May 27 (Neg. Box 16)
    Notes: "May 26 3 small spots on Eastern limb. Two of the small spots visible on May 26 have disappeared, and the one that is seen with the glass is too small to come into the picture."
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Barton, 1876 Jun 17 2:10 PM (Neg. Box 9)
    Notes: "Two groups; some change since yesterday."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Harrison, 1876 Sep 28 (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "Two large groups of spots coming on, Each group surrounded by spots of very small size, not seen in the photograph."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Harrison, 1876 Sep 29 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "One of the groups seen in the photograph of Sept 28 has separated into two."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Harrison, 1876 Oct 2 (Neg. Box 25)
    Notes: "Two groups on the western limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Harrison, 1876 Oct 3 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "The group passing off. - Oct. 9-10 No spots (plates destroyed)"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1876 Oct 13 (Neg. Box 3)
    Notes: "3. Spots few."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1876 Oct 13 [2:03 PM?] (Neg. Box 16)
    Notes: "A small group of small spots going off."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1876 Oct 18 12:04 PM (Neg. Box 17)
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1876 Oct 19 2:15 PM?] (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "A group of spots coming on. Only one was visible on Oct. 18, but today, Oct. 19 this is followed by two very small ones. Faculae visible around the group. - Oct. 30th No spots (plate destroyed)."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1876 Oct 30 12:03 PM (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "No spots. - Nov 13 A very small spot on eastern limb. - Nov 16. A very [small spot?] moving across the disc and a pair of large spots coming on - Nov 24 These large spots had disappeared and faculae were visible on the western limb, near the edge - Nov 27 No spots - Dec 1, 3, 5 No spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by [unknown], 1876 Nov 10 (Neg. Box 16)
    Notes: "Duplicate taken at 12.15."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1876 Dec 20 12:35 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "A large spot followed by several small ones coming on."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1876 Dec 23 12:35 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "A large spot accompanied by one rather smaller. Below these a very small spot and two some distance, behind a very small pair of spot."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Jan 12 12:40 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "A large spot coming on, followed by two very small ones which do not appear in the photograph – On Jan. 4 a very faint spot was observed on the eastern limb. On Jan. 9 The faint spot was observed on the western limb and on the eastern limb a pair of very faint ones. These were no longer visible Jan. 12."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Jan 13 [2:15 PM?]; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 20)
    Notes: "The last spot mentioned in the last record Jan 12. is still on the eastern limb. It is followed by two very small ones not seen in the photograph. Another large spot is just coming on."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Jan 14 12:33 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "The two large spots seen in the picture of Jan. 13 appear to be moving regularly – One of the two very small ones which were observed following the large spot on the eastern limb, is no longer visible. The large spot coming on is surrounded by faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Jan 18 12:50 PM (Neg. Box 19)
    Notes: "The large group of spots near the center of the disk consists of three spots irregular in shape surrounded by a chain of faint spots. The small spot which followed the spot which is now on the western limb has disappeared."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Jan 18 [1:12 PM?] (Neg. Box 25)
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Jan 19 (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "A regular motion of the single spot and the group is observed."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Jan 23 [1:00 PM?] (Neg. Box 34)
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Jan 23 12:45 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "One of the large spots visible in the last picture has passed off, the other is near the edge."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Jan 24 (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "The spot is very near the edge and is surrounded by faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Feb 7 [2:00 PM?] (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "A large spot coming on."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Feb 8 [1:49 PM?] (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "A large spot on the eastern limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Feb 9 12:25 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "A spot on the eastern limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Woodward, 1877 Feb 10 12:50 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "A spot approaching the center. The spot seems to be about 15 degrees from Equator."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Feb 13 12:40 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "The spot is approaching the center."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Feb 14 12:55 PM (Neg. Box 34)
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Feb 14 12:55 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "The spot is now on the western limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Feb 15 12:45 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "The spot is now on the western limb. On Feb. 14 a very small spot was observed accompanying the large one."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Mar 1 12:50 PM (Neg. Box 34)
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Mar 1 12:40 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "A large group is visible near the center and a small spot above."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Mar 3 12:35 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "The motion appears regular"
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Mar 5 12:45 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "The small spot has not been seen since Mch. 3. The group, consisting of a large spot surrounded by several small ones too small to appear in the picture, is now on the western limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Mar 6 (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "The small spots, which have been observed, in the group now on the western limb are no longer visible. The two spots near the center have suddenly appeared. They were not seen Mch. 5."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Mar 7 2:02 PM (Neg. Box 19)
    Notes: "The motion of the spots appears regular. Mch. 8. The group was still visible. Mch. 9 The Sun's disc was free from spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Mar 21 12:30 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "On mch. 18 a large group of spots was first seen – 60 degrees from the equator, South in the telescope. On Mch 21 spots occupied the position shown in the photograph. From Mch. 21 to April 8 observations were – interrupted by clouds. But, when the sun's limb(?) could be seen, it appeared free from spots. On April 8 a very small spot was observed, on the eastern limb. A more powerful glass resolved this spot into two and showed faculae around. April 13th – No spots – (plate destroyed)"
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Apr 17 12:25 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "On April 14th the limb appeared to be free from spots. On April 15 there was observed two large spots followed by a cluster of small ones near the center. On April 16 these were seen on the western limb. On April 17 there appeared to be a change in the grouping of the spots, and a very large one was followed by a cluster and a single spot, as seen in the photograph."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Apr 23 12:19 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "From April 17th to April 21 Clouds prevented observation. On April 21 a pair of spots was observed on the eastern limb. On April 22 this pair was seen to have moved on, while, on the eastern limb a pair of very small ones made their appearance. Both pairs are now visible, April 23."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Apr 24 12:28 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "A regular motion is observed in the spots seen in the photograph of April 23, but the number and arrangement of the spots has changed, there being now a chain of spots near the center, and, a chain of very small ones on the eastern limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Apr 25 12:25 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "The spots in the group now on the western limb have decreased in number and size, while in the group now near the center there has been an increase in number and size of the spots. April 26 1877 No change is observed, except in position."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Apr 30 12:30 PM (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "A very small group of spots surrounded by faculae was observed coming on April 29. This group was very far from the center, north in the telescope. It does not appear in the photograph."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 May 4 12:30 PM; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "The small group mentioned in the – of April 30 is still -- -- telescope but it does not appear in the photograph."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 May 6 12:38 PM; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "The small group first seen on April 29 was last seen May 5 about at the center of its course but very faint. On May 6 it could not be found. On May 5 a small spot followed by a faint small spot was seen on the western side of the center. This had not been seen May 4."
  - Sunspots, observed by, 1877 May 8 12:35 PM (Neg. Box 34)
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 May 12 12:35 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "Two large spots near the center—For some days clouds have prevented observation"
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 May 14 12:26 PM (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "One of the spots seen in the picture of May 12 has disappeared. The others appear to be moving regularly. The two were visible on May 13."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Hazard, 1877 Jun 1 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 32)
    Notes: "No Spots. "
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Barton, 1877 Jun 16 12:20 PM (Neg. Box 9)
    Notes: "Group coming on—also two small spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by Spalding and Hazard, 1878 Jan 28 [12:12 PM?]; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "No spots. Feb. 16 No spots (plate destroyed) Feb. 20 No spots (plate destroyed)"
  - Sunspots, observed by Spalding and Hazard, 1878 Feb 5 [12:12 PM?] (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "A string of about 12 small spots near center of disc."
  - Sunspots, observed by Spalding and Hazard, 1878 Feb 6 11:55 AM (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "Several small spots passing off."
  - Sunspots, observed by Spalding and Hazard, 1878 Mar 5 12:05 PM (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "Two very mall spots passing off disc. - March 6th No spots (plate destroyed) - March 8th No spots (plate destroyed)"
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1878 Mar 10 (Neg. Box 16)
    Notes: "A spot surrounded by faculae coming on."
  - Sunspots, observed by Spalding and Hazard, 1878 Mar 15 12:10 PM (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "3 spots of -- -- double, passing of the disk [some words along the edge have disintegrated along with the paper.]"
  - Sunspots, observed by Spalding and Hazard, 1878 Mar 15 12:20 PM (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "3 spots of which one is double, passing off the disc."
  - Sunspots, observed by Spalding and Hazard, 1878 Mar 16 12:01 PM; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "Some spots that were seen Mar. 15th near edge of disc and fainter. [March 19-21] no spots - March 22. No spots, plate destroyed."
  - Sunspots, observed by Spalding and Hazard, 1878 Mar 23 12:25 PM (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "No spots. - March [25-26, 29-30] No spots, plates destroyed - April [1-2, 8] No spots, plates destroyed"
  - Transit of Mercury, observed by Spalding, 1878 May 6 12:00 PM (Neg. Box 1)
    Notes: "Mercury is well on to the disc; This is good."
  - Transit of Mercury, observed by Spalding and Hazard, 1878 May 6 10:40 AM (Neg. Box 36.7)
    Notes: "Mercury has just entered"
  - Transit of Mercury, observed by Spalding and Hazard, 1878 May 6 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 1)
    Notes: "The negative is very poor, but the planet is seen easily - [Maria Mitchell] (included is a drawing of the exact placement of the shadow of Mercury on the Sun.)"
  - Transit of Mercury, observed by Spalding and Hazard, 1878 May 6 1:26 PM (Neg. Box 36.8)
    Notes: "Mercury in Transit"
  - Sunspots, observed by Spalding and Abbot, 1878 May 17 [12:12 PM?]; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "Plate destroyed. No spots. - May 18, 22-24 no spots, plates destroyed."
  - Sunspots, observed by Spalding and Hazard, 1878 May 29 12:05 PM (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "One single spot and one group consisting of three individual spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1878 Jun 22 (Neg. Box 9)
    Notes: "Same group; faculae"
  - Sunspots, observed by Hazard and Macy, 1878 Sep 25 12:25 PM; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "No spots. Sept. [27, 30] No spots (plates destroyed) - Oct. [2-5, 10] No spots (plates destroyed)"
  - Sunspots, observed by Hazard and Braden, 1878 Nov 4 12:30 PM (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "One small spot to the right and above the center. The first spot visible since Sep. 22"
  - Sunspots, observed by Hazard and Dow, 1878 Nov 5 12:20 PM (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "The same spot as in Nov. 4 further to the right."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hazard and Dow, 1878 Nov 7 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "The same spot as in Nov. 4 and 5. - Nov. 14th no spots. Plate destroyed."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hazard and Armstrong, 1879 Apr 8 12:10 PM; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "No spots. "
  - Observed by Hazard and Mott, 1879 May 9 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 19)
  - Sunspots, observed by Hazard and Mott, 1879 May 10 12:10 PM (Neg. Box 19)
    Notes: "Same spot as in May 9. moved further on."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hazard and Hodge, 1879 May 12 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 19)
    Notes: "No spot visible* in photograph. Same spot of May 9 and 10. viewed with large telescope May 12 and found to consist of four small ones. Too small on that day to be viewed with – survey telescope. * I think the spots are seen here – [Maria Mitchell]"
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Arnold, 1879 Nov 10 12:45 PM (Neg. Box 19)
    Notes: "Spots. Duplicate."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Arnold, 1879 Nov 10 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 19)
    Notes: "Group of two large spots with small ones surrounding them. Situated on lower edge toward the right. First seen Nov. 7."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1879 Nov 24 11:45 AM; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 14)
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1879 Dec 2 11:45 AM (Neg. Box 19)
    Notes: "Spots seen at right of center."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1879 Dec 3 11:45 AM (Neg. Box 19)
    Notes: "Same spots as Sun Dec. 2."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1879 Dec 5 11:45 AM; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "Sun spot last seen near the center of the sun has suddenly disappeared."
  - Saturn, observed by [Hodge?], circa 1880 (Neg. Box 36.28)
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 Jan 21 11:45 AM; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "No spots. There is something which looks very much like a spot toward the middle."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 Feb 2 12:02 PM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "Three groups of spots. Duplicate"
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 Feb 2 12:10 PM; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "One group of large and two groups of small spots seen on Sun. First seen Jan. 31. They were then some distance from the edge."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 Feb 4 12:02 PM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "Same spots of Feb. 2, with another small one which has just come on the sun (there is also a diagram of the sun depicting this explanation of the spots.)"
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 Feb 5 12:05 PM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "Same spots of Feb. 4, which have advanced more to the left. The one just on the sun has a surrounding of faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and [E. M. Mame?], 1880 Feb 6 11:55 AM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "Same spots as seen Feb. 4. Duplicate"
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and [E. M. Mame?], 1880 Feb 6 11:45 AM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "Same spots of Feb. 4, which have moved toward the left. Two small ones and faculae seen around the one nearest the edge."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 Feb 9 11:40 AM (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "The spots of Feb. 4 are moving to the left limb of Sun. Another group of spots suddenly appeared Feb. 8, beyond the center. The wind was blowing a – when this picture was taken. But four groups of spots may be on the limb of the Sun which is near the second seen."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Lathrop, 1880 Feb 10 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "Four groups of spots seen on limb of Sun which is next the second impression. Feb. 11 and 12 were cloudy, but the spots were still seen on the afternoon of Feb 12 near the limb of Sun."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Bush, 1880 Feb 14 12:15 PM; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 14)
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 Feb 24 11:55 AM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "One group of spots with faculae has just appeared on the Sun. No more photographs obtained till Feb. 27 on account of rain and cloudiness."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Bush, 1880 Feb 27 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "The group of spots has advanced about halfway across the Sun"
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 Mar 1 11:45 AM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "One group of spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 Mar 4 11:45 AM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "Small spot seen on edge of sun near it's – of fallow(?) -."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 Mar 8 11:45 AM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "Two groups of spots seen in photograph."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 Mar 10 11:45 AM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "One group of spots seen"
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 Apr 10 11:45 AM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "Small spots seen on edge which is next to second seen"
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Cady, 1880 Apr 27 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "A long row of spots is seen near the zenith a little past – of Sun. There were many clouds and the wind was blowing hard when this picture was taken. The four preceding days were cloudy and these spots were first seen today."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 May 1 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 17)